In November 2009,Uncle Marshall and Aunt Lily
2009年11月 Marshall叔叔和Lily阿姨
hosted the first Thanksgiving at their very own apartment.
第一次在自己小窝里 主办筹备了的感恩节晚餐
And Marshall had found the perfect turkey.
Marshall还找到了最好的火鸡
Oh,baby,it is beautiful.
亲爱的 它真美
It's 22 pounds. It's organic.
重达22磅 全有机饲料喂养
You remember my bald Uncle Heinrek?
还记得我的光头叔叔Heinrek吗?
It looks exactly like his head.
跟他的头简直一模一样
Oh,my God.
噢天呐
My turkey...
我的火鸡...
My turkey!
我的火鸡!
So,when we showed up for the big day,
当天我们到达的时候
Marshall was pretty bummed out.
Marshall看上去很憋气
Well,we got the turkey.
好吧 我们有火鸡了
No. You didn't. You got the pathetic replacement turkey.
不 才没有 你们的火鸡是杯具的替代品
Damn it,you know,why didn't I just listen to the precorded voice
该死 为什么在车里我没听前市长Ed Koch
of former Mayor Ed Koch reminding me to take my belongings?
"不要遗忘随身物品"的提醒录音?
No,Marshall,you don't understand.
不 Marshall 你没明白
Robin and I went to the Port Authority Lost and Found,
Robin和我去了事务局的失物招领处
and there,sitting in their fridge...
在那里 静静坐在他们冰箱里的是...
Marshall Eriksen...
is this your turkey?
这是你的火鸡吗?
Yes! That's my turkey!
对! 就是我的火鸡!
Oh,come here,you handsome little bastard!
噢 过来  你这只帅气的小混蛋
Okay,I'm going to go put this in the oven.
好吧 我把它放进烤箱
Okay. Oh,my God! You guys are the best friends ever!
好吧 噢 天呐! 你们是有史以来最好的朋友了!
It was totally a team effort.
绝对是团队合作的成果
I'm so ha...
我实在太...
Guys,I don't know what to say.
朋友们 我都不知道该说什么了
I mean,it's Thanksgiving,
我是说 今天是感恩节
but "thanks" just doesn't seem like enough.
但是光一个"谢"字貌似远远不够
Come on,buddy,you would've done the same thing for us.
别这样 兄弟  换做你也会为我们这么做的
Yeah,I would,and you know why?
是的 我会的 你们知道为什么吗
Because I love you guys.
因为我爱你们
And I'm going to show you just how much.
马上 你们就会知道我对你们的爱有多深
Ted Mosby,Robin Scherbatsky,I bequeath unto you the fourth slap.
Ted Mosby和Robin Scherbatsky 我将把第四个巴掌转交给你们
Wait,what?
等等 什么?
Kids,you remember Barney and Marshall's "Slap Bet.
孩子们  你们还记得Barney和Marshall的"掌掴赌注"吗?
" When Barney lost,Marshall won the right
Barney输了后
to slap Barney five times as hard as he could.
Marshall赢得了掌掴Barney五次的奖励 想多用力就多用力
So far,he'd used three of those five slaps.
至今为止 他已经用掉三个巴掌
With the third being doled out
随着第三个巴掌的使用
exactly two years earlier on Thanksgiving Day 2007.
那次正好也在两年前 2 007年的感恩节
A day that history came to know as "Slapsgiving.
历史上记载此天为"掌掴节"
" Are you saying...
你的意思...
...what we think you're saying?
...是不是我们所想的那个意思?
Probably not.
也许不是
Unless you think I'm saying "Slapsgiving Two:
除非你认为我指的是 "掌掴节2: 掌掴复仇记"
Revenge Of The Slap," in which case,yes,
如果是这样的话 是的
that's exactly what I'm saying!
那就是我想说的!
No way!
没门!
Uh-uh. Slaps aren't transferable.
不不 掌掴人不能换成其他人
Lily is the Slap Bet Commissioner. Lil?
Lily是掌掴公证人  Lil你说呢
Slaps are transferable.
掌掴人可以转移
- No! - Transferable!
- 不! - 可以转移!
Wait,Marshall,you realize you'll only have one left after this.
等一下 Marshall 你要知道 使用掉这个就只剩最后一个了
Are you sure you want to spend this slap today?
确定要在今天扇这一巴掌吗?
Life is short. I figured,Slap-e Diem.
人生苦短 我已悟出了真谛  掌掴才是王道
Okay,rule number one: the slap must occur before sundown,
好吧 规矩一 掌掴必须在天黑前完成
so as not to interfere with Lily's meal.
以免搅乱Lily用餐
Damn straight.
说的没错!
Two,you guys have to decide amongst yourselves who gets to do it.
规矩二 你们必须自己决定谁来扇这一巴掌
Three... we're going to tie Barney to this chair,
规矩三 我们会把Barney绑在这张椅子上
which shall henceforth be referred to as The Slapping Throne. Sound fair?
今后这张椅子就被称为"掌掴王座" 公平吧?
- Totally. - Amazing.
- 很公平 - 真神奇
Absolutely not!
当然不公平!
It was all set to be the best Thanksgiving ever.
那本来会是最棒的感恩节
Until...
直到
Are we expecting somebody else?
我们在等人吗?
It was someone Lily hadn't seen or spoken to in three years.
等的人正是Lily三年都没有见过面  没有说过话的
Dad.
爸爸
how i met your mother s05e09
-=伊甸园美剧论坛 http://bbs.sfileydy.com=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=- Proudly Presents
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=- 翻译: 午桑 花竹梗  校对: 祈求RP的小毛毛 时间轴: 卡灰
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=- Sync: 卡灰
老爸老妈浪漫史 第五季第九集
Now,Lily and her dad,Mickey,
现在 Lily和她的爸爸Mickey
had always had a tough relationship.
关系一直不融洽
Mickey's dream was to invent the next great American board game.
Mickey的梦想是发明最牛的美式桌游
But his ideas were always a little off.
但他的创意总不太靠谱
- Daddy? - Yeah?
- 老爸? - 嗯?
You missed my ballet recital.
你错过了我的芭蕾独舞
Yes,sweetie,but,look!
是的 亲爱的 但是你瞧
I just put the finishing touches
我刚装饰完毕
on my new,hit board game,"Tijuana Slumlord.
新的热门棋盘游戏  "提华纳的万恶地主"
- " Daddy? - Uh-huh?
- 老爸? - 嗯哼?
You missed my gymnastics meet.
你错过了我的体操比赛
Yeah,yeah,yeah. Butthisis the one!
是啊 是啊 但是就是它了
"Car Battery:
"汽车电池: 你能坚持多久"
How Long Can You Hold On?
" Here,Princess. Grab these.
过来 小公主 抓住这个
- Daddy? - Mm-hmm.
- 爸爸? - 嗯哼
I had a nightmare.
我做了个恶梦
Aw,sweetie.
噢 宝贝
Here,come play Daddy's new game:
过来玩爸爸的新游戏
"There's A Clown Demon Under The Bed!
"床底有个小丑魔鬼"
" Her whole life,Mickey disappointed Lily.
她一生中 Mickey都让她失望
And she always put up with it,
但她一直默默忍受着
until one day in 2006 when Lily went to visit her grandparents.
直到2006年的一天  Lily去看望她的爷爷奶奶
So,Rita,are you excited about the,uh, the big move to Florida?
Rita 马上要搬到佛罗里达洲了  开心吗?
Actually,dear,slight change of plans.
事实上 亲爱的  计划稍有变动
We're staying here for the time being.
我们暂时还是住这里
We had a slight financial hiccup.
我们出了点财务小状况
Ma! The straw to my juice box broke!
妈妈 我的果汁盒上的吸管断了
Ma,chop,chop!
妈妈 恰恰恰
Oh,hey,guys.
噢 嗨 大家好
What a pleasant surprise.
多让人高兴的一个惊喜
Dad,what happened to your apartment?
爸爸 你怎么不在你的公寓?
Oh,well,I had a little falling out with my roommate.
噢 我和室友吵架了
- What happened? - He wanted me to pay rent. Got kind of ugly.
- 怎么了? - 他想让我付房租 然后事情就变得有点棘手了
Dad! You should be paying rent,not living in your parents' basement.
爸爸! 你应该付房租 而不是住在父母的地下室里
Hey,it's not my first choice.
喂 最初我可不想来这里的
Having the old farts right upstairs is crimpin' my style a bit.
楼上住着两个老骨头 让我的形象大打折扣
Clearly,they're not getting the whole
很显然 他们还是不知道
"sock on the doorknob" thing.
"门把上的袜子"的真正含义
Oh,they caught you with a girl?
噢 他们看到你和一个女孩XXOO了?
In a way.
差不多吧 (估计是在DIY)
Bye,sweetheart. I'm off to work.
再见 亲爱的 我要去上班了
Work? You're retired.
上班? 你已经退休了啊
Now that I have an extra mouth to feed,
现在多了个人要养活
I had to go back to the steel mill.
我得回钢铁厂
Rita? Where's my truss?
Rita 我的疝气绷带呢?
So,not only did you stop them from moving to Florida,
你不仅成了他们搬去佛罗里达州的障碍
but now you forced Grandpa to go back to work?
还逼迫爷爷回去工作?
Just until I get Aldrin Games Unlimited off the ground
只要等到我把Aldrin游戏公司挤走
with my new sensation:
用的就是我的新发明:
"Dog Fight Promoter.
"狗狗之战的赞助商"
" And then Lily gave her dad a look
然后Lily用一种表情看着他
that Marshall had only seen a few times before.
这种表情Marshall也仅看过几次
A look we all prayed never to be on the receiving end of:
那个 我们这辈子都不想收到的
her "You're Dead To Me" look.
她那"对我而言你已死去"的表情
Which brings us back to Thanksgiving of 2009.
回到2009年的感恩节
Hey,Princess.
嗨 小公主
I brought "Diseases!
我带来了"疾病游戏"
- do that? - I don't know,but maybe we should,
- 他来干吗? - 不知道 也许我们应该...
uh,let him in and find out.
让他进来看看他想干吗
No,I don't want to see him! Get rid of him!
不 我不想见到他  让他走
Hey,Mickey.
嘿 Mickey
Just hang tight,okay?
再等一会 好吗
We'll,we'll work this out.
我们 我们会搞定的
Take your time,amigo.
没关系的 伙计
I'm okay as long as I have "Diseases!
只要我有"疾病游戏" 我就不会有事的
" The fun's infectious.
游戏的乐趣可是会传染的哦
God,I hope Lily's okay.
天啊 我希望Lily没事
Me,too.
我也是
She doesn't talk about it much,
她不太提起这事
but this thing with her dad causes her a lot of pain.
但是她和爸爸的事给她带来很多痛苦
Just tell me which one of you's gonna slap me!
只要告诉我 你们中的谁要扇我巴掌
- What? - I'm dying over here!
- 什么? - 我生不如死!
Ted reaches for a chip,I flinch!
Ted拿薯片时 我躲开了
Robin fixes her hair,I flinch!
Robin理头发时 我躲开了
I'm doing so much flinching. It's bad for my skin.
我躲地太频繁 皮肤会变差的
I'm getting crow's feet. Crow's feet!
都快变鸡爪皮了 鸡爪皮!
Lily,come on. It's been three years,okay?
Lily 不要这样 都过去三年了
That's long enough.
也够久了
Having him in my life causes me nothing but stress.
有他在我的生活中  只会给我带来压力
It's just easier for him to be dead to me.
把他想象成已死对我来说比较容易
Okay,Lily,look.
好吧 Lily 瞧
I supported you when our neighbor,Mr. Ossias,was "dead to you.
你把我们的邻居Ossias先生视为已死 我支持你
" Hey! That's our newspaper.
嘿! 那是我们的报纸
You'll get it back in 15 minutes.
15分钟内还给你们
Make it 20. I had a steak last night.
20分钟吧  昨晚我吃了块牛排
And I was fine when your bridesmaid, Whitney,was "dead to you.
你把你的伴娘Whitney视为已死  我也支持你
" Oh,Lily! You look so amazing!
噢 Lily 你看上去美极了
That dress is gorgeous!
这衣服美极了
Oh,thanks,guys.
噢 谢谢大家
Hmm,I... I'm just not a fan of strapless.
呃 我...我就是不太喜欢无肩带的款式
I even understood
我甚至能理解
when Mr. Park from the bodega downstairs was "dead to you.
你把楼下小店的Park先生视为已死
" One coffee,please.
一杯咖啡
Oh,but only if you have decaf.
噢 但是只要无咖啡因的
I don't want to be up all night.
我不想整宿睡不着
Dollar fifty.
1块5
Coffee,regular.
来杯普通咖啡
Dollar fifty.
1块5
Excuse me. Are you sure mine was decaf?
不好意思 你确定我的是无咖啡因的吗?
You just used the same pot.
你用的是同个咖啡壶
Oh,I lie to him. Okay?
噢 我对他撒谎了 好吗?
Oh,okay.
噢 好吧
You son of a bitch.
你个狗娘养的
That was not decaf!
那不是无咖啡因的
I supported you with all of those random people,
对这些无关痛痒的人 我都支持你
but this is your father.
但他是你的父亲
Okay,can't we at least just give him some turkey?
好吧 我们至少得给他点火鸡吧?
- No. - Come on,Lily.
- 不 - 不要这样嘛 Lily
Please,I can't ask the guy to leave on Thanksgiving.
求你了 我不能在感恩节赶走一个人
Oh,you don't have to ask.
噢 你不用请他走
Just tell him that it's really important that he be here.
只要告诉他 他能留下对你来说很重要
And before you know it,
在你回过神来前
he'll be at a board game convention in Toledo,
他就已经在托莱多的一个棋类游戏研讨会上了
giving your braces money to some guy
把你的钱交给一个
claiming to be Milton Bradley.
声称自己是Milton Bradley的人了 (北美最早的棋类游戏公司创始人)
He was just out trying to provide for the family.
他只是想出去挣点钱补贴家用
No. No,that's what my mom did by working two jobs.
不 不  是我妈妈做两份工才维持了家用
Marshall,that man broke my heart
Marshall 那个男人伤透了我的心
every single day for 20 years.
20年来的每一天都如此
Well,then we'll just give him some dark meat.
好吧 那我们就给他点鸡腿肉吧
No,seriously,Robin,you should get the slap.
不 我说真的 Robin 该由你来掌掴
I mean,you're a great slapper.
我是说 你掌掴很厉害
In fact,I want to study slapping under your tutelage.
事实上  我还想在你的指导下学习掌掴之道呢
I want to be your slap-prentice.
我想做你的掌掴学徒
Don't sell yourself short there,Teddy.
别低估你自己 Teddy
You're a slapping rock star.
你是个掌掴巨星
Your name should be Eric Slapton.
你的名字应该是Eric Slapton
Okay,okay,guys,this is torture.
好吧 好吧 大伙 这简直是折磨
- Just put me in the chair... - Slapping Throne.
- 把我弄到椅子上... - 掌掴王座上
- And get it over with! - Okay,he's all yours.
- 赶紧扇了这一巴掌吧! - 好吧 他归你了
No-no-no-no. It's you,I insist.
不 不 不  他是你的 我发誓
- Okay,I'll do it. - Great. Wait,what?
- 好吧 我来 - 好极了 等等 什么?
I'm just saying,I'll slap him.
我只是说  我来扇他耳光
What,so that's just,like,the end of the discussion?
什么 所以这就...讨论结束了?
Well,you said I could slap him.
是你说我可以掌掴他的
Uh,I was just being nice.
呃 我只是跟你客套一下
If anyone's gonna slap him,it's gonna be me.
如果有人要掌掴他  那人也得是我
No,it's not.
不 不是的
This is interesting.
真有趣
Lily,he's family,okay?
Lily 他是你的家人 好吗?
And I'm sorry,but you just don't cut off family.
对不起 我不想拆散一个家庭
Oh,well,that's easy for you to say
你说起来容易
when you come from the most ridiculously close family in the world.
你来自一个世界上亲近地不可思议的家庭
We are not ridiculously close.
我们才不是亲近地不可思议呢
- Really? - Yeah.
- 是真的吗? - 是的
What about the Eriksen Family Dinner every single Sunday?
Eriksen家每周日的聚餐怎么说?
Everything looks delicious,Mother Eriksen.
一切看上去都那么美味 Eriksen妈咪
Thank you,Papa Bear.
谢谢 熊爸爸
Marshall,would you like to say grace?
Marshall 饭前祷告你来做好吗?
Well,I would be happy to,Mother.
我很乐意 妈妈
Everyone,please join hands.
各位 请拉手
Dear Lord...
亲爱的主...
I'm sorry,but that's weird.
抱歉 真是太另类了
A family should be that close.
一家人就该这么亲密无间
And I want our future family to be that close.
我希望我们未来的家庭也能这样
And that includes your dad.
当然也包括你爸爸
I can't believe you're taking his side.
真不敢相信你帮他说话
- Lily... - Let me be clear on this:
- Lily... - 我再重申一遍
that man will never cross the threshold into this home,ever!
那人永远别想踏进我家的门槛!
It's just gonna be,like, five more minutes.
再等大概五分多钟就行
Hopefully soon,amigo.
但愿快点 朋友
I'm fighting a losing battle with hemorrhoids here.
同痔疮搏斗 我注定要吃败仗
Oh,that's one of the diseases?
这是疾病游戏的一种吗?
No.
不是
Ted,there is an hour before the sun sets,
Ted 再过一小时太阳就下山了
at which point,neither one of us gets to slap Barney.
到现在还没决定谁搧Barney
So just let me have it.
那就让我来吧
I'm the one who had the idea to call the Port Authority Lost and Found.
是我想到给港务局失物招领处打电话的
Ooh,that's a good point. Rebuttal?
有利的论据 反方?
I'm the one who slipped the guy a 20!
是我给那家伙塞20块的
Oh,philosophical conundrum.
哲学难题
Idea versus execution.
创意与执行的碰撞
Please discuss at length.
请做总结陈词
I carried that huge turkey all the way up here.
是我千里迢迢把火鸡拿上来的
I paid for cab fare.
出租车钱是我给的
Well,you slept with one of my best friends!
你和我死党上床!
What?!
什么?
You,you said you were okay with that.
你 你说不介意的
Well,I'm not!
我介意
Well,why didn't you say something at the time?
那你当时为什么不说?
Because I'm still in love with you!
因为我还爱着你!
Do you really want to slap Barney so bad
你真那么想搧Barney?
that you would lie about being in love with me?
不惜撒谎说还爱着我
I really want to slap him,okay?
我真超想搧他 好不?
Yes,your dad has made some mistakes in the past,
是 你爸过去是犯过错
but he's a different person now.
但他现在改过自新了
He's moved out of your grandparents' house.
他从你爷爷奶奶家搬出来了
He's got a job.
找了份活
He's paying off his IRS debts.
开始偿还欠税
Wait,how do you know all that?
等等 你怎么知道这些的?
Like,body language.
看肢体语言
Okay,well,yeah,we met for a drink last week.
好吧 我们上周出去喝酒了
I miss her a ton.
我好想她
Little princess.
小公主
She ever talk about me?
她有说起过我吗?
Yeah. Yeah,like,all the time.
嗯 嗯 总说起
Um,she tells this one really sweet story about...
她说过那啥的温馨往事
- So never,huh? - No,not a word.
- 从没说过 哈? - 嗯 只字未提
But... it doesn't have to be that way.
但...事情还有转机
We can,we can fix this,right?
我们能弥补 对吧?
You know,I always thought it'd get fixed at the wedding.
我一直想在你们婚礼上作出补偿
I even wrote a toast.
我都写好了祝酒词
But then,no invite.
但没邀请我
Hell,I haven't even seen a wedding photo.
我都没见过你们的结婚照
And then,right before my eyes,
接着 当着我的面
your father broke down crying.
你父亲哭了起来
That's it!
好了!
You're coming to Thanksgiving!
感恩节你来吧!
You invited him?!
你邀请他了?!
The guy was,like,blubbering.
他都泪如雨下了
What was I going to do?
我能怎么办?
And then,some jerk at the next table called him a sissy,
隔壁桌有个混蛋骂他娘娘腔
which I thought was totally uncalled-for.
简直是胡说八道
I can't believe you.
我不相信
Marshall,what gives you the right to do that?
Marshall 你有什么权利这么做?
You and I are married.
你嫁给了我
And that means he's my family,too.
就是说他也是我家人了
Mickey,come on in.
Mickey 快进来
Ted,you better roll quickly.
Ted 你快点掷骰子
Your gall bladder's about to burst.
你的胆囊快爆了
You know,Mickey,it's been,like,half an hour.
Mickey 都半个小时了
I think we should go look for Lily.
我觉得我们该去找找Lily
Eh,she just needs some time to cool down. Let's finish the game.
她需要点时间冷静下 我们先把游戏玩完吧
Yeah,play another round. Best of seven!
嗯 再战一局 七战四胜!
Damn it,Robin!
靠 Robin!
I've known Barney the longest.
我早认识Barney了
I get to slap him.
该我来搧他
That slap is mine,Mosby.
该我 Mosby
I've never slapped Barney...
我从没搧过Barney
above the waist.
腰以上的部位
Look,I've wanted to slap Barney since the moment I met him!
听着 从我瞅见Barney那会儿 我就想搧他!
You don't think that I want to slap Barney?
你觉得我不想搧Barney吗?
- I've waited... - Wait,wait a minute. Wait a minute!
- 我都等了... - 等下 等下!
This slap was supposed to be a wonderful thing,
这耳光本该是件好东西
a gift,and look,it's turned us against each other.
是份礼物 瞧瞧 我们为它争起来了
My God,you're right.
我的天 你说得对
This once pure fruit has turned into a poison slapple.
纯洁的友谊之果变成毒苹果
You know what? Seriously,you take it.
说真的 你拿去吧
Are you sure?
你确定?
Slapsolutely.
斩钉截铁
I really think that we should go look for Lily.
我真觉得该去找下Lily
Ted? Gall bladder about to pop.
Ted? 胆囊要爆了
Okay,it's decided. Barney,come on. Get in the Throne.
好吧 决定了 Barnry 来吧 登上宝座
- Hmm? Are you... - Yep. Come on.
- 呣? 你... - 对 来吧
Well,you,um... Uh,well,I guess that is the best decision,Robin.
你 呃...我觉得这决定妙极了 Robin
I mean... men are stronger than women.
我是说...男人比女人强
D-Don't listen to him.
别听他的
- Okay,it's been decided. - Okay.
- 好吧 已经决定了 - 好吧
And that's what you've always wanted,isn't it,Robin?
这是你一直想要的 不是吗 Robin?
A strong man to take care of you?
一个强大的男人来照顾你?
I mean,sure. Growing up,you were a scrapper.
小宇宙爆发吧 你可是打架的好手
Playing hockey with the boys,skinning your knees on the ice.
和男孩一起玩曲棍球 在冰面上擦破膝盖
But what you couldn't tell your teammates--
但你难以向你队友启齿
what you couldn't even tell yourself--
甚至无法向自己启齿的是
was that all you really wanted
你内心想要的
was that pretty white dress in that pretty white chapel.
只是华丽丽的白色小礼服 和华丽丽的白色小教堂
And at the end of that center aisle,
在走道的尽头
strewn with pretty white flowers,
铺满华丽丽的白花
a man to do all your slapping for you.
一个男人替你打点好一切
- Let me at him! - Robin! Come on! Hold on!
- 让我搧他! - Robin! 拜托! 冷静!
Oh,my God.
我的天
- What just happened? - Sorry,Ted. Gallbladder burst.
- 发生了什么事? - 抱歉 Ted 胆囊爆了
You move back three spaces.
你得退三步
You come in here,
你来这
and you watch your daughter leave
眼睁睁看着自己的女儿走掉
and you don't even care.
都无动于衷
And now you've destroyed Thanksgiving dinner!
现在你又毁了感恩节大餐!
Lily-Lily worked all day on this!
Lily Lily为这忙活了一天!
Relax. It's not real bile.
别鸡冻 又不是真的胆汁
It's just lead-based paint from China.
只是中国产的含铅油漆而已
And horse bile.
混着马的胆汁
And at that moment, Marshall gave Mickey a look
就在那时 Marshall用我们
none of us had ever seen him give anyone.
从没见过的眼神瞪着Mickey
What's this? What's he doing?
这是啥? 他在干吗?
Did you swallow some of that paint?
你吞下油漆了?
This is my "you're dead to me" look.
这眼神的意思是"你对我来说已死"
Oh. Oh. Okay.
好吧
Yeah,you know,Lily's is so much better...
嗯 Lily的厉害多了...
Get out of my house!
滚出我家!
Mr. Park's,huh? This is the last place I expected to find you.
Park咖吧 哈?  我没想到你在这里
- Marshall... - Lily,I'm sorry. But just hear me out.
- Marshall... - Lily 对不起 听我把话说完
I used to think that family was-was a right. But it's not.
我一直以为家人之间就该那样 但我错了
It's a privilege,and it has to be earned.
并非所有人都能这样 得付出努力才行
I kicked your dad out.
我把你爸赶出去了
And I promise,baby,I will...
我保证 宝贝 我...
I will never make you see him again.
我决不会再逼你见他了
Oh,what? Baby,what-what happened?
怎么? 宝贝 发生什么事了?
Marshall,I came in here because it was cold
Marshall 我来这是因为外面太冷
and this was the only place that was open.
只有这里还开着
I wasn't even gonna look Mr. Park in the eye.
我都不想正视Park先生
And then I found out...
然后我发现...
Mr. Park died.
Park先生死了
Oh,my God.
我的天
He really is dead to me!
他真的已经死了!
And if I feel this bad about never making up with Mr.Park,
我真后悔没能和Park先生和好
a guy who meant literally nothing to me...
尽管他对我来说无足轻重...
We got to go get my dad.
我们得去找我爹
Okay.
好的
So that's how on Thanksgiving 2009,
这就是2009年的感恩节
your Aunt Lily performed a miracle.
你们的Lily阿姨妙手回春
She brought a man back from the dead.
从鬼门关救了个人回来
Everyone.
各位
Before we get started,Barney,
在开始前 Barney
we're going to need you on The Slapping Throne.
我们要你坐在掌掴宝座上
Slap Bet Commissioner, surely tying me to a chair is a breach...
掌掴裁判 把我绑椅子上是犯规行为...
Yeah,yeah,yeah. Less yappin',more slappin'.
嗯嗯 少废话 多搧搧
Ted,Robin. It's two minutes until sundown.
Ted Robin 还有两分钟就天黑了
Have you guys decided which one of you
你们决定由谁
is going to get to slap Barney right in his face?
搧Barney一大嘴巴了吗?
It's gonna be Ted.
是Ted
What? Why me?
啥? 为啥我?
Last year,you got left at the altar.
去年 你的新娘逃婚
You lost your job.
你又丢了工作
But you've come such a long way since then.
但你都挺过来了
I'm so proud of you,Ted.
我真为你骄傲 Ted
You deserve to slap someone in his face as hard as you can.
使劲搧别人一大嘴巴是你该得的
- Thanks. - This is the worst.
- 谢谢 - 倒霉透了
Mama!
妈妈!
No,Robin. Look...
不 Robin 听着
You just went through your own breakup,and...
你刚从失恋的阴影里走出来...
while I know you and Barney left it on good terms,
我知道你和Barney关系还好
isn't there some part of you,deep down,
难道你内心深处不想
that wants to slap him right in his face?
搧他一大嘴巴吗?
- There is. - I know there is.
- 想 - 我就知道
This is basically hell on Earth.
真是人间炼狱
All right. You got this.
好的 给你了
It hurts!
好痛!
No. I can't do it.
不 我办不到
I can't take this from you,Ted.
我不能从你那夺走 Ted
- Nor I,you. - Oh,thank God.
- 我也是 - 谢天谢地
So,I'd like to make a gesture.
我想做个决定
- Mickey? - Oh,no way!
- Mickey? - 不行!
I'm glad you and Lily are trying to work things out.
很高兴你和Lily能和好如初
So,to welcome you to our little family...
为了欢迎你加入我们的小家庭
I'd like to offer you this slap.
我想把搧耳光的机会给你
Really?
真的?
Well,I feel a little weird.
我觉得有点怪
I-I just met Barney,
我和Barney萍水相逢
and I don't have anything against the guy,
又没啥过节
but how often do you get a chance
然而你能有几次
to slap someone right in his face?
搧别人大嘴巴的机会?
Soft!
轻点!
I'm sorry. I can't do it.
抱歉 我办不到
Oh,thank God.
谢天谢地
Lily...
I know I haven't been much of a father to you.
我知道自己这个爸爸并不称职
You are kidding me.
你开什么国际玩笑
So for all the ballet recitals that I missed,
作为所有我没能到场的
for all the art shows that I should've been at...
芭蕾舞演出和文艺演出的补偿
...for the wedding gift that I never got a chance to give to you...
还有一直没机会给你的结婚礼物
Princess...
小公主
I give this slap to you.
我把搧耳光的机会给你
Oh,Daddy!
爸爸!
No. No,no,no,no.
不不不
She is the Slap Bet Commissioner.
她是掌掴裁判
She's supposed to remain impartial!
她该保持中立!
Slap Bet Commissioner says it's okay.
掌掴裁判说行就行
This is not good.
这可不妙
Okay.
好吧
Please,please,please. Let me... Let me...
拜托 拜托 让我...让我...
Just close your eyes. It'll be over soon.
闭上眼睛 马上就好了
Running through a meadow.
在大草原上奔跑
I can't do it. Why can't I do it?
我办不到 为啥我办不到?
Because this slap has done exactly what I hoped.
因为这记耳光的目的已经达到
It's brought us all closer together.
它让我们更紧密
And it's caused us to recognize
它让我们明白
both the frailty and the greatness in ourselves and each other.
彼此的脆弱和坚强
Oh,give me a break.
让我消停会吧
And that is why...
所以...
there will be no slap today.
今天不用搧耳光
Oh,my God!
我的天!
This is the best Thanksgiving...
这个感恩节太美好啦...
That's four!
第四下!
So,uh,turkey?
火鸡呢?
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=- Proudly Presents
-=伊甸园美剧论坛 http://bbs.sfileydy.com=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=http://bbs.sfileydy.com=- Sync: 卡灰
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=- 翻译: 午桑 花竹梗  校对: 祈求RP的小毛毛 时间轴: 卡灰
how i met your mother  s05e09
老爸老妈浪漫史 第五季第九集